export let easyQuestions = [
    {
        id: 1,
        question: "Who is considered the first emperor of rome?",
        questionContext: "The Roman emperor was the ruler of the Roman Empire during the imperial period. The emperors used a variety of different titles throughout history. Often when a given Roman is described as becoming 'emperor' in English it reflects his taking of the title augustus (and later basileus). Another title often used was caesar, used for heirs-apparent, and imperator, originally a military honorific. Early emperors also used the title princeps civitatis ('first citizen'). Emperors frequently amassed republican titles, notably princeps senatus, consul, and pontifex maximus. ",
        options: [
            "Octavian","Ceaser","Diocletion"
        ],
        correctOption: 1
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        question: "It is generally accepted that the Western Roman Empire fell in the year : ",
        questionContext: "By ____, the position of Western Roman Emperor wielded negligible military, political, or financial power, and had no effective control over the scattered Western domains that could still be described as Roman. Barbarian kingdoms had established their own power in much of the area of the Western Empire. In ____, the Germanic barbarian king Odoacer deposed the last emperor of the Western Roman Empire in Italy, Romulus Augustulus, and the Senate sent the imperial insignia to the Eastern Roman Emperor Flavius Zeno. ",
        options: [
            "1453","476","1066"
        ],
        correctOption: 2
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        question: "It is generally accepted that the Eastern Roman Empire fell in the year : ",
        questionContext: "The conquest of Constantinople and the fall of the Byzantine Empire was a watershed of the Late Middle Ages and is considered the end of the medieval period. The city's fall also stood as a turning point in military history. The Walls of Constantinople (Theodosian Walls), were some of the most advanced defensive systems in the world. These fortifications were overcome with the use of gunpowder, specifically in the form of large cannons and bombards, heralding a change in siege warfare. Refugees fleeing the city after its capture would settle in Italy and other parts of Europe, helping to ignite the Renaissance",
        options: [
            "1453","476","1066"
        ],
        correctOption: 1
    },
    {
        id: 4,
        question: "Where is the Hagia Sophia Located",
        questionContext: "Built by the eastern Roman emperor Justinian I as a Christian cathedral of the Roman Empire between 532 and 537, the church was then the world's largest interior space and among the first to employ a fully pendentive dome. It is considered the epitome of Byzantine architecture. It remained the world's largest cathedral for nearly a thousand years, until Seville Cathedral was completed in 1520.",
        options: [
            "Rome","Byzantium","Lugdunum"
        ],
        correctOption: 2
    },
    {
        id: 5,
        question: "What was the capital of the roman diocese of the east?",
        questionContext: "The Diocese of the East (Latin: Dioecesis Orientis; Greek: Διοίκησις Ἑῴα) was a diocese of the later Roman Empire, incorporating the provinces of the western Middle East, between the Mediterranean Sea and Mesopotamia. During late Antiquity, it was one of the major commercial, agricultural, religious and intellectual areas of the empire, and its strategic location facing the Sassanid Empire and the unruly desert tribes gave it exceptional military importance.",
        options: [
            "Antioch","Byzantium","Alexandria"
        ],
        correctOption: 1
    },
    {
        id: 6,
        question: "The Great Emperor Diocletion is remembered today as somebody who established : ",
        questionContext: "Diocletian (/ˌdaɪ.əˈkliːʃən/; Latin: Gaius Aurelius Valerius Diocletianus; c. 242/245 – 311/312) was Roman emperor from 284 to 305. Born to a family of low status in Dalmatia, originally named Diocles, Diocletian rose through the ranks of the military to become a cavalry commander of the Emperor Carus's army. After the deaths of Carus and his son Numerian on campaign in Persia, Diocletian was proclaimed emperor by the troops. Diocletian's reign stabilized the empire and ended the Crisis of the Third Century allowing him to separate and enlarge the empire's civil and military services while reorganizing the empire's provincial divisions",
        options: [
            "Democracy","Principate","Serfdom"
        ],
        correctOption: 3
    },
    {
        id: 7,
        question: "The Last Great Western Roman Emperor : ",
        questionContext: "The situation became critical in 408, after the death of Stilicho, a general who tried to reunite the Empire and repel barbarian invasion in the early years of the 5th century. The professional field army collapsed. In 410, the Theodosian dynasty saw the Visigoths sack Rome while experiencing a significant reduction of its territory. The Vandals conquered North Africa, the Visigoths claimed the southern part of Gaul, Gallaecia was taken by the Suebi, Britannia was abandoned by the central government, and the Empire suffered further from the invasions of Attila, chief of the Huns. General Orestes refused to meet the demands of the barbarian 'allies' who now formed the army, and tried to expel them from Italy. Unhappy with this, their chieftain Odoacer defeated and killed Orestes, invaded Ravenna and dethroned Romulus Augustus, son of Orestes. This event of 476, usually marks the end of Classical antiquity and beginning of the Middle Ages.",
        options: [
            "Julius Nepos","Majorian","Honnorius"
        ],
        correctOption: 2
    },
    {
        id: 8,
        question: 'The Epithet "The Last Of The Romans" is frequently given to',
        questionContext: "Justinian's ambition to restore the Roman Empire to its former glory was only partly realized. In the West, the brilliant early military successes of the 530s were followed by years of stagnation. The final victory in Italy and the conquest of Africa and the coast of southern Hispania significantly enlarged the area of Byzantine influence and eliminated all naval threats to the empire, which in 555 reached its territorial zenith. Despite losing much of Italy soon after Justinian's death, the empire retained several important cities, including Rome, Naples, and Ravenna, leaving the Lombards as a regional threat. The newly founded province of Spania kept the Visigoths as a threat to Hispania alone and not to the western Mediterranean and Africa. ",
        options: [
            "Belisarius","John","Narses"
        ],
        correctOption: 1
    },
    {
        id: 9,
        question: "Date on which the festival of Sol Invictus was celebrated",
        questionContext: "The Roman gens Aurelia was associated with the cult of Sol. After his victories in the East, the Emperor Aurelian thoroughly reformed the Roman cult of Sol, elevating the sun-god to one of the premier divinities of the Empire. Where previously priests of Sol had been simply sacerdotes and tended to belong to lower ranks of Roman society, they were now pontifices and members of the new college of pontifices instituted by Aurelian. Every pontifex of Sol was a member of the senatorial elite, indicating that the priesthood of Sol was now highly prestigious. Emperor Aurelian instituted games in honor of the sun god, held every four years from 274 onwards. ",
        options: [
            "14 February","25 December","1st May"
        ],
        correctOption: 2
    },
    {
        id: 10,
        question: "The Capital Of Roman Gaul",
        questionContext: "Gaul (Latin: Gallia) was a region of Western Europe first described by the Romans. It was inhabited by Celtic and Aquitani tribes, encompassing present day France, Luxembourg, Belgium, most of Switzerland, and parts of Northern Italy, the Netherlands, and Germany, particularly the west bank of the Rhine. It covered an area of 494,000 km2 (191,000 sq mi). According to Julius Caesar, Gaul was divided into three parts: Gallia Celtica, Belgica, and Aquitania. During the 2nd and 1st centuries BC, Gaul fell under Roman rule: Gallia Cisalpina was conquered in 204 BC and Gallia Narbonensis in 123 BC. Julius Caesar finally subdued the remaining parts of Gaul in his campaigns of 58 to 51 BC.",
        options: [
            "Burdigala","Paris","Lugdunum"
        ],
        correctOption: 3
    },
]